Preliminary remark:

GISAD wants to develop a digital social system from the perspective of Europe's citizens, which can hold its own in system competition.

The aim of GISAD is to support the creation of a holistic Marshall Plan, as proposed by the President of the European Commission Ursula von der Leyen. The core of the Marshall Plan
must be a digital concept adapted to civil rights and diversity. If individual measures are taken without an Europe runs the risk of losing the system competition against other economic areas such as a centrally controlled China. such as a centrally controlled China.

GISAD calls for the creation of a one-stop shop for a Marshall Plan. Only when the basic assumptions of an overall digital concept are understood and agreed upon is the prerequisite for
an evaluation of the results of the consultations is possible (multiple use of the same infrastructure without additional costs). GISAD's statement is subject to this reservation.

Challenges:
We find ourselves in increasing system competition with offerings that have emerged in the USA in the social consensus after 9/11 and in China in the social consensus of surveillance through a social credit system. The European response for a digital system that can hold its own in this system competition must be better and more comprehensive. This is why GISAD rejects a pure software solution for digital identification. Many attempts to install such solutions in the past in have failed because they are too inconvenient for the citizen. These solutions are inconvenient if only occasional applications are found and the citizen then has to remember the have to remember the functionalities. On the other hand, they can be integrated into already monopolistic gatekeeper portals and strengthen them to the detriment of the citizen. and strengthen them to the detriment of a European digital structure. Moreover, the preservation of anonymity is only possible if no personal data is stored on the internet at all. The The power to dispose of the data must remain with the citizen at all times.

Objective against the background of an overall digitalisation strategy:

An overall system must be created in which EU citizens are given real power of disposal over their data. With this system, they must be able to move easily in a European internet, shop anonymously and, if possible, leave no traces on the internet. On the other hand, citizens must have access to complete forensic data evidence in individual cases and after a court order. A backup of the data must be ensured. For this purpose, hardware is needed in addition to software, as well as a regional network of trust stations through which personalisation can be established. The hardware (USB-Stik) must be made available to all EU citizens free of charge. It must be possible to find, encrypt and store all data - including data stored in the office - via a central search. A value creation concept must be placed on top of this to ensure that there are no gatekeepers and that the value creation is distributed according to performance. The system, consisting of hardware and software, must be made available to all EU citizens free of charge.

The somewhat higher costs for such a system will be refinanced in the shortest possible time if the concept is supported by by a political and social consensus.

For a new overall digital concept, GISAD accordingly calls for the free provision of a citizens' rights infrastructure for all EU citizens (see on this: https://youtu.be/doPXxmX7fec?t=233 , https://youtu.be/XZS1YGTULIw?t=57 and https://youtu.be/s1occJG5SOw?t=29)

In which an IP address can be unambiguously assigned to the person responsible for a piece of information, a product, a service or a machine. service or machine.
Consisting of regional trust stations in the residence of an EU citizen, with a state recognition equivalent to a notary.
With the assignment of a unique public IP subnet to each trust station.
With the issuance to each EU citizen by a trust station of 1,000 IP addresses randomly generated from the IP subnet.
With the obligation of the trust station to only assign the IP addresses assigned to the EU citizen to personal data in such a way that their storage location is physically separated from the Internet (no network connection).
With the right of the trust station, without direct knowledge by the EU citizen concerned, to negotiate with a judge during a specific investigation. in the event of a specific investigation, to negotiate with a judge which data (belonging to a category, period of time, occurring in a specific geographical area) must be released.
With the obligation of the trust station after a reasonable period of time to inform the EU citizen concerned about the surrender and the of the surrender and to ensure WAN anonymity (WAN means WIDE AREA NETWORK) by issuing new IP addresses.
In which the storage of personal data over the Internet in relation to the citizens' rights infrastructure is technically and legally prevented.
In which the physical power of disposal over keys and identities and the content created over them rests with the individual citizen.
In which security is ensured by the provision of hardware created exclusively in Europe. (USB stick as an extension of any device).
In which all metadata, symmetric keys and identities for the data used are stored in such a way that the power of disposal over the data lies with the individual citizen.
In which an automatic update option is created (e.g. when a device is loaded), which ensures that EU citizens the availability of their metadata and ensures forensic digital evidence in the event of a house search.
